Lombard in focus to discuss the third
quarter performance Mr gopal
balachandran is Chief Financial Officer
of the company and we he's with us now
to take some questions sir good morning
great to have you with us here as always
Prashant theide so your f524 n ear
premium stood at about 17,000 crores 9
months 25 number in terms of net ear
premium is
14,575 crores do you think you can add
about 5,000 crores in Q4 to cross 20,000
crores for the full year 25
so good morning prant to you and all
your viewers uh so I think if you look
at uh from an IC Lombard standpoint uh I
think this I kind of talked about even
in the uh some of your earlier calls I
think what we're looking for is uh I
think on the growth front in terms of
premiums uh is to continue to see if we
can have an alpha over the industry
growth I think we have broadly talked
about a range of uh 100 to 200 basis
points I think that is where we stand I
think specific in the context of net
earned premium I think that has a lot of
moving Parts because different
businesses have uh different risk
retention uh thought processes so but I
think where we are kind of placed for is
to try and continue to see uh an alpha
over the industry growth of 100 to 200
basis points and that's what you would
have seen even on a 9 Monon basis the
industry grew on premiums at roughly
about 7 8% our growth was roughly at
about 10.3% so that's where we are uh
different segments I think each of them
presents an opportunity to continue to
leverage on that Mr Bal but I know you
don't want to put specific numbers but
in the ballpark these this seems doable
20,000 crores for the full year in the
ballpark yeah so I think I think see
what we have largely spoken to the
market is in the context of the industry
because as I said uh there will be lot
of moving Parts in terms of how things
play out uh so in that context is where
I think I would kind of say that uh what
we largely monitor as a metric is to
look at alpha or industry growth and
more importantly I think what we also
keep looking for is how we can continue
to deliver sustained uh return to
stakeholders okay Mr balachandran uh so
the operation performance is very good
uh the underwriting losses they've
reduced considerably I think the the
drop is about 46% operating profits have
been surging just walk us through what
led to this one I think in the fire
segment you've taken a premium hike I'm
not sure by how much how much have
average premiums gone up in health but
just run us through the trends and what
the the expectation is for the coming
couple of months as well super good
morning to you and uh let me again just
put this in context um I think again if
you look at this this year's 9month
numbers have has got uh an element of I
would say a regulatory change uh for
example effective first of October uh
the regulator has introduced a new way
of recognizing uh premiums for long-term
policies as in to say that in the past
if an insurance company would have
collected a premium on a long-term
policy the entire premium would have got
recognized offr and similarly any cost
of acquisition that you would have
incurred would also have kind of got
recognized offr uh effective 1 October
both of them changes as in to say that
the premiums will get recognized on a 1
byn prescription that is to say that it
will be amortised over the contract
period and similar will be the case in
the context of
cost so hence when you look at now
specific to your point on the
underwriting result given the fact that
you had the element of an amortization
of acquisition cost over the uh policy
cycle there is obviously an improvement
in underwriting that uh one has seen and
that's what we also put out specifically
as a separate slide also post our
earnings call to reflect what has been
this impact of change consequent to the
commissions getting deferred its impact
on the operating profit numbers so that
number is roughly on a profit before tax
basis roughly about 60 crores but more
than the absolute numbers will be I
think I would kind of continue to urge
uh all of your viewers and the market at
large to keep looking at more the
outcome on the combined ratio because
that's largely a reflection of the
insurance operations and there pretty
much we are on track in terms of the
Glide part that we have spoken about
which means that your combined ratio
should drop to about
10.5% right by when so should again I
think I think again I'll put that in
context I think because even in my
earlier calls I think I get kind of
indicated that from an is Lombard
standpoint we would obviously want to
continue to see uh our combin ratios
better than the overall Market but if
you look at the half year numbers for
the industry uh which is available at a
trailing quarter first half of last year
the combin ratio for the industry was
111 this year's combin ratio is roughly
about 113 now if this trend line
continues then obviously we can't
suddenly see a significant
outperformance Vis the market while we
will continue to have a Delta uh so
hence I think we are on track whether it
is in terms of growth whether it is in
terms of managing claims or even in
terms of operating outcome but obviously
I think the trajectory is looking very
very positive if the industry continues
to remain sensible in terms of outcomes
there is no reason why we should not get
to that combin of 101.5 or even better
than that but you not specify the time
sir is it this fiscal or are you pushing
that Target to fi 26 so which is why I
think we'll have to wait for the results
to kind of play out that's the reason
why I said this has to be looked at in
context and then obviously as I said if
the market responds favorably there is
no reason why we should not get to that
combin of 10 1.5 earlier okay so uh just
to go back I take your points one is the
regulatory change in the manner in which
you know the uh premiums are being
recognized that's been one factor
overall you're saying combined ratio
will keep moving down uh just that word
on uh in general how you see premiums
Rising fire there's been an increase on
health what do you see ahead and
therefore I come back to the point that
you know will uh operating profits keep
improving going forward as well and to
what extent will that be a function of
the hike in uh in premiums yeah
especially on health so that's a great
question again but again markets are
where they are right they obviously will
remain competitive and therefore to that
extent is how we will have to see things
play out but having said that I think
your point is absolutely right on the
insurances that you have been extending
to operates which is the commercial
lines in the last nine months we did
that we did see that segment exhibiting
price pressures and that's the reason
unlike the preceding 10 years where we
would have normally is lard would have
gained market share this year our market
share has remained muted in commercial
lines as a category but the good news is
exactly what you refer to I think
effective January 1 the pricing
discipline seems to be seems to be
looking up quite positively but the real
impact of the price change on the
commercial lines is something that we
will see when bulk of the corporate
renewals happen on April 1 but overall
direction or trajectory is looking
positive in the context of commercial
lines on health to your specific point
two segments corporate health and Retail
Health on corporate Health we continue
to see uh pricing pressure and therefore
to that extent from an Isis Lombard
standpoint our philosophy of carefully
selecting risks stays intact and hence
to that extent we have actually kind of
let go some of the portfolios in the
context of corporate Health on retail I
think the Investments that we have
spoken about in distribution and the
launch of uh new products for example in
quarter to the new Health Solution ele
that's been received very well now there
again if you look at the loss ratio
range that the retail health book is
exhibiting is around the range that we
have spoken about at about 70% and a lot
of work for us for Isis Lombard is
happening in the context of claims
management but equally in case if the
portfolio warrants any kind of a price
change we have not Shi away from taking
one
all right uh we'll leave it there Mr
balandran thank you very much for
joining us uh pleasure thank you good
luck well the